[English subtitles are available]
[الترجمة الإنجليزية متوفرة]
[Pretty Guardian of the City]
[الحارس الجميل للمدينة]
[Episode 17]
[الحلقة 17]
Look at that color.
انظر إلى هذا اللون.
So ugly.
قبيح جدا.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
I'm changing it for you.
أنا أغيره من أجلك.
No need.
لا حاجة.
Such a strange color.
يا له من لون غريب.
Is it from a girl?
هل هي من بنت؟
Is it from Yunxi?
هل هو من يونشى؟
I knew it.
كنت أعرف.
Only she would choose
هي فقط من ستختار
such a tacky color.
مثل هذا اللون المبتذل.
I like it.
أحبها.
Stop right there!
توقف هناك!
You took hers,
لقد أخذت لها ،
so you have to take mine too.
لذلك عليك أن تأخذ خاصتي أيضًا.
Miss.
يغيب.
Take it back. I don't want it.
استعيدها.  لا اريدها.
If you dare to return it,
إذا كنت تجرؤ على إعادته ،
I won't talk to you again.
لن أتحدث معك مرة أخرى.
Miss,
يغيب،
please don't force me.
من فضلك لا تجبرني.
Tang Qing,
تانغ تشينغ ،
I hate you so much!
انا اكرهك كثيرا!
Miss.
يغيب.
Do you want to know your fortunes?
هل تريد أن تعرف ثرواتك؟
Marriage. Destiny.
زواج.  مصير.
Future. Wealth.
مستقبل.  ثروة.
I can look at the flowers and tell your fortunes.
أستطيع أن أنظر إلى الزهور وأخبر عن حظك.
Are you interested?
هل انت مهتم؟
No. Let's go.
رقم دعنا نذهب.
Judging from your faces,
انطلاقا من وجوهكم ،
you are destined to be together.
أنت مقدر أن تكون معًا.
In the future,
فى المستقبل،
you will be a loving couple
سوف تكونا زوجين محبين
and live happily together.
والعيش معًا بسعادة.
What are you talking about?
ما الذي تتحدث عنه؟
How's it possible that he's the one for me?
كيف يمكن أن يكون هو الشخص المناسب لي؟
Miss, you haven't paid.
آنسة ، لم تدفع.
Nonsense.
كلام فارغ.
You need to pay me more or less.
عليك أن تدفع لي أكثر أو أقل.
You...
أنت...
Poor me.
المسكين أنا.
My brother's condition is getting worse.
حالة أخي تزداد سوءًا.
I can't even get him to drink the ginseng soup.
لا يمكنني حتى أن أجعله يشرب حساء الجينسنغ.
He won't last long if this goes on.
لن يدوم طويلاً إذا استمر هذا.
I want to go to the Xiao's Mansion again.
أريد أن أذهب إلى قصر شياو مرة أخرى.
No way.
مستحيل.
Fengchi
فنغتشي
is not in Commander Xiao's hands.
ليس في يد القائد شياو.
The rumors
الشائعات
about Fengchi
حول Fengchi
were perhaps spread
ربما انتشرت
by someone deliberately.
من قبل شخص ما عمدا.
I spread
انتشرت
those rumors.
تلك الشائعات.
So it was a trap
لذلك كان فخًا
you set up.
قمت بإعداده.
You planned to lure out
كنت تخطط للإغراء
the one who took the Swing Painting.
الشخص الذي أخذ لوحة الأرجوحة.
But I accidentally
لكنني بالصدفة
fell into
سقطت
your trap.
فخك.
I didn't expect
لم أتوقع
you to visit the Xiao's Mansion that night.
عليك أن تزور قصر شياو في تلك الليلة.
It's my fault that you were stabbed.
إنه خطأي أنك تعرضت للطعن.
Fine.
بخير.
I'll take it as a blessing in disguise.
سوف أعتبرها نعمة مقنعة.
I saved your life
لقد أنقذت حياتك
and we're together now.
ونحن معا الآن.
But there's one thing
لكن هناك شيء واحد
I don't understand.
لا أفهم.
If the Swing Painting
إذا كانت اللوحة المتأرجحة
is really in my uncle's hands,
في يد عمي حقًا ،
why hasn't he found Fengchi
لماذا لم يجد Fengchi
in the past eight years?
في السنوات الثماني الماضية؟
Actually,
في الحقيقة،
I'm confused about that too.
أنا في حيرة من أمري بشأن ذلك أيضًا.
But I'm sure
لكن أنا متأكد
that the Swing Painting is in the Xiao's Mansion.
أن اللوحة المتأرجحة في قصر شياو.
Maybe there's something tricky
ربما هناك شيء صعب
about the Swing Painting
حول لوحة التأرجح
and Commander Xiao
والقائد شياو
hasn't figured it out.
لم أحسبها.
Since you're sure about where it is,
نظرًا لأنك متأكد من مكانه ،
let's find a way
لنجد طريقة
to get it first.
للحصول عليه أولاً.
However,
لكن،
you can't take the risk
لا يمكنك المجازفة
of breaking into the Xiao's Mansion again.
لاقتحام قصر شياو مرة أخرى.
But my brother…
لكن أخي ...
Leave it to me.
اتركه لي.
If we don't want
إذا كنا لا نريد
to alert my uncle again,
لتنبيه عمي مرة أخرى ،
we have to bide our time
علينا أن نتحمل وقتنا
to get the Swing Painting.
للحصول على لوحة التأرجح.
My brother has been lying here alone
كان أخي يرقد هنا بمفرده
for so long.
لفترة طويلة.
He must be very lonely.
يجب أن يكون وحيدًا جدًا.
After he wakes up,
بعد أن يستيقظ ،
I will take him back to the Jianjia Alley.
سأعيده إلى زقاق جيانجيا.
With all of us
معنا جميعًا
around him,
حوله،
he'll be very happy.
سيكون سعيدا جدا.
So,
لذا،
you still want to go back to the Jianjia Alley.
ما زلت تريد العودة إلى زقاق جيانجيا.
It's shabby,
إنه رث ،
but my home is there.
لكن منزلي هناك.
[The Blueprint of Cangyue City]
[مخطط مدينة كانغيو]
Maybe
يمكن
I should tear down the Jianjia Alley.
يجب أن أهدم زقاق جيانجيا.
Young Master, are you crazy?
سيد الشاب ، هل أنت مجنون؟
It was an effort for us to save it.
لقد كان جهدًا لنا لإنقاذه.
Why did you have a change of heart?
لماذا غيرت قلبك؟
You fool.
يالك من أحمق.
You know what?
أتعلم؟
Yunxi's childhood
طفولة يونكسي
was very miserable
كان بائسا جدا
and depressing.
والاكتئاب.
I want to do something for her.
أريد أن أفعل شيئًا لها.
Money and jewelry
النقود والمجوهرات
are too vulgar.
مبتذلة جدا.
I want to rebuild her home for her.
أريد إعادة بناء منزلها لها.
Young Master,
المعلم الصغير،
I doubt it will work.
أشك في أنه سوف يعمل.
Why?
لماذا ا؟
In my opinion,
فى رايى،
you should rebuild
يجب عليك إعادة البناء
the whole Winding Alleys.
الأزقة المتعرجة بأكملها.
I bet you also want
أراهن أنك تريد أيضًا
to build a mansion
لبناء قصر
in that slum
في ذلك الحي الفقير
which will become an easy target for thieves.
الذي سيصبح هدفًا سهلاً للصوص.
Good idea.
فكره جيده.
Young Master,
المعلم الصغير،
I was joking.
كنت امزح.
You didn't take it seriously, did you?
أنت لم تأخذ الأمر على محمل الجد ، أليس كذلك؟
Rebuilding the Winding Alleys will cost a lot.
إعادة بناء الأزقة المتعرجة سيكلف الكثير.
Even the City Treasury
حتى خزانة المدينة
may not be able to afford it.
قد لا تكون قادرة على تحمله.
You underestimate me.
أنت تقلل من شأني.
Do you think
هل تعتقد
I'm as stupid as you?
أنا غبي مثلك؟
You know you're no better than me.
أنت تعلم أنك لست أفضل مني.
Go back to your work.
عد إلى عملك.
Listen.
استمع.
Don't let Yunxi know about this.
لا تدع Yunxi يعرف عن هذا.
Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
Don't talk to her
لا تتحدث معها
in the next three days.
في الأيام الثلاثة المقبلة.
Otherwise…
خلاف ذلك…
I think we'd better
أعتقد أننا أفضل
trust each other more
نثق في بعضنا البعض أكثر
and be more friendly to each other.
وأن نكون أكثر صداقة مع بعضنا البعض.
You've been in the study for so long.
لقد كنت في الدراسة لفترة طويلة.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
I'm learning
أنا أتعلم
mapping skills.
مهارات رسم الخرائط.
Really?
هل حقا؟
Tell me.
أخبرني.
Are you holding out on me?
هل تمسك بي؟
No.
رقم.
We should be honest with each other.
يجب أن نكون صادقين مع بعضنا البعض.
If you lie and keep secrets,
إذا كنت تكذب وتحتفظ بالأسرار ،
I'll be sad.
سأكون حزينا.
That's not necessarily right.
هذا ليس صحيحًا بالضرورة.
In fact,
في الواقع،
sometimes white lies
في بعض الأحيان أكاذيب بيضاء
can bring us
يمكن أن تجلب لنا
closer to each other.
أقرب لبعضهم البعض.
So,
لذا،
you admit that you are holding out on me?
هل تعترف بأنك تتمسك بي؟
Can't you just be honest with me?
ألا يمكنك أن تكون صادقًا معي فقط؟
Wuyan has told me everything.
أخبرني وويان بكل شيء.
An imbecile he is.
إنه معتوه.
I just want to give you a surprise.
أنا فقط أريد أن أعطيك مفاجأة.
That's not a surprise.
هذه ليست مفاجأة.
It's a bombshell.
إنها قنبلة.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
Have those aristocrats
لديك هؤلاء الأرستقراطيين
gone back on their word?
تراجعوا عن كلمتهم؟
You couldn't stand the pressure
لا يمكنك تحمل الضغط
and decided to tear down
وقررت هدمها
the Winding Alleys.
الأزقة المتعرجة.
[Draft of rebuilding the Jianjia Alley into Futian Institution.]
[مشروع إعادة بناء زقاق جيانجيا وتحويله إلى مؤسسة فوتيان.]
Don't you want to take your brother
لا تريد أن تأخذ أخيك
back to live in the Jianjia Alley?
العودة للعيش في زقاق جيانجيا؟
So I want to rebuild
لذلك أريد إعادة البناء
the Jianjia Alley.
زقاق جيانجيا.
I wanted to give you a surprise.
أردت أن أعطيك مفاجأة.
It's all Wuyan's fault. That stupid guy.
كل هذا خطأ وويان.  هذا الرجل الغبي.
He'll be fined three months' salary.
سيتم تغريمه براتب ثلاثة أشهر.
Three months are not enough.
ثلاثة أشهر غير كافية.
Make it three years.
اجعلها ثلاث سنوات.
Okay.
تمام.
The Winding Alleys to the south
الأزقة المتعرجة في الجنوب
are an old
هي قديمة
and messy neighborhood.
وحي فوضوي.
People there
الناس هناك
are living in tough conditions.
يعيشون في ظروف صعبة.
They also seriously affect
هم أيضا يؤثرون بشكل خطير
the overall layout and beauty
التصميم العام والجمال
of Cangyue City.
من مدينة كانجيو.
So I think
لذلك أعتقد
we should tear down the Winding Alleys
يجب علينا هدم الأزقة المتعرجة
and build Futian Institution there.
وبناء مؤسسة فوتيان هناك.
But this is a serious matter.
لكن هذه مسألة خطيرة.
You can't come up with it
لا يمكنك الخروج بها
on a whim
لمجرد نزوة
and expect us all to agree.
ونتوقع أن نتفق جميعًا.
As for the expense of building Futian Institution,
أما عن حساب بناء مؤسسة فوتيان ،
I've written clearly about it
لقد كتبت عنها بوضوح
in the proposal.
في الاقتراح.
[Proposal]
[عرض]
Please take a look, Father.
من فضلك الق نظرة ، أبي.
The City Treasury
خزانة المدينة
will find the money spent worth it.
سيجد المال الذي أنفقه يستحق ذلك.
Young Master, you're not in charge of the City Treasury
السيد الشاب ، أنت لست مسؤولاً عن خزانة المدينة
so you don't know about it.
لذلك أنت لا تعرف عنها.
The City Treasury can't afford such expense.
لا تستطيع خزانة المدينة تحمل مثل هذه النفقات.
Our city has been developing slowly these years
مدينتنا تتطور ببطء هذه السنوات
and taxes have been reduced.
وخفضت الضرائب.
We don't have extra money.
ليس لدينا أموال إضافية.
Well...
نحن سوف...
I know
أنا أعرف
you proposed to rebuild the Winding Alleys
اقترحت إعادة بناء الأزقة المتعرجة
for the well-being of the people.
من أجل رفاهية الشعب.
I don't object to it
أنا لا أعترض على ذلك
and I won't.
ولن أفعل.
But I'm afraid
لكنني خائف
you have to pay for it out of your own pocket.
عليك أن تدفع ثمنها من جيبك الخاص.
Uncle,
اخو الام،
you can't say that.
لا يمكنك قول ذلك.
Everyone standing here
الجميع يقف هنا
is a pillar of Cangyue City.
هي أحد أعمدة مدينة كانغيو.
We all should strive for
يجب علينا جميعًا أن نسعى من أجله
the well-being of the people.
رفاه الناس.
Since the City Treasury is cash-strapped,
بما أن خزانة المدينة تعاني من ضائقة مالية ،
in my opinion,
فى رايى،
Uncle should take the lead
يجب أن يأخذ العم زمام المبادرة
to donate some money
للتبرع ببعض المال
for the construction of Futian Institution.
لبناء مؤسسة فوتيان.
Sorry to disappoint you, Young Master,
آسف لإحباطك ، سيد الشباب ،
but I've made
لكني صنعت
lots of donations these years
الكثير من التبرعات هذه السنوات
and don't have
وليس لديك
much savings.
الكثير من المدخرات.
However,
لكن،
Young Master's proposal
اقتراح ماجستير الشباب
will greatly benefit our people.
سوف يفيد شعبنا بشكل كبير.
Therefore,
وبالتالي،
even if everyone in my household
حتى لو كان كل فرد في منزلي
has to tighten our belts,
يجب أن يشد أحزمةنا ،
I'll be the first one to support Young Master.
سأكون أول من يدعم السيد الشاب.
I'll donate
سوف أتبرع
a month's salary.
راتب شهر.
I'm glad to make a bit of a contribution
يسعدني أن أقدم القليل من المساهمة
to the construction of Futian Institution.
لبناء مؤسسة فوتيان.
Master,
يتقن،
I don't have money,
ليس لدي نقود
but I'm willing to
لكنني على استعداد لذلك
sell the house I prepared for my retirement
بيع المنزل الذي أعددته لتقاعدي
to support Young Master!
لدعم السيد الشاب!
You've been pretending to be ignorant in the meeting hall
كنت تتظاهر بالجهل في قاعة الاجتماعات
and using all your wits to deal with your uncle
واستخدام كل ما تبذلونه من الذكاء في التعامل مع عمك
for all these years.
لكل هذه السنوات.
It must have been hard for you.
لا بد أنه كان صعبًا عليك.
Father,
أب،
you finally
انت اخيرا
recognize my efforts.
تعترف بجهودي.
I'm so glad.
أنا جد مسرور.
Why don't you also donate some money
لماذا لا تتبرع أيضًا ببعض المال
to build Futian institution?
لبناء مؤسسة فوتيان؟
Cut the crap.
قطع الفضلات.
Zhu Wen is my man.
تشو ون هو رجلي.
You must have known it.
يجب أن تكون قد عرفت ذلك.
So I'll be honest with you.
لذا سأكون صادقًا معك.
I've been watching
لقد كنت اشاهد
your every move.
كل تحركاتك.
Since you were young,
منذ كنت صغيرا
I've liked you the most among your siblings.
لقد أعجبت بك أكثر من بين إخوتك.
You're the smartest one
أنت الأذكى
and are just like me.
وهم مثلي تمامًا.
But now...
لكن الآن...
You...
أنت...
Father.
أب.
Enough.
كافية.
Actually, I know
في الواقع ، أنا أعلم
you have no other options.
ليس لديك خيارات أخرى.
Raising money to rebuild the Winding Alleys
جمع الأموال لإعادة بناء الأزقة المتعرجة
is very hard.
من الصعب جدا.
But you have to do it
ولكن عليك أن تفعل ذلك
for the prosperity
من أجل الازدهار
of our people
من شعبنا
and to make them
ولصنعها
live a better life.
عش حياة أفضل.
You must do your best.
يجب أن تبذل قصارى جهدك.
I support you from the bottom of my heart.
أنا أدعمك من أعماق قلبي.
Then...
ثم...
What about the donation?
ماذا عن التبرع؟
I...
أنا...
I support you mentally.
أنا أدعمك عقليا.
So stingy.
بخيل جدا.
-So glib. -What are you murmuring?
-إذاً عفويًا.  -ماذا تتذمر؟
I said I really admire you.
قلت إنني معجب بك حقًا.
Thank you for your support, Father.
شكرا لك على دعمك يا أبي.
If there's nothing else,
إذا لم يكن هناك شيء آخر ،
I'll take my leave.
سآخذ إجازتي.
Wait.
انتظر.
Now let's talk about family affairs.
الآن دعنا نتحدث عن شؤون الأسرة.
Your mother fell sick because of you.
والدتك مرضت بسببك.
Why haven't you visited her?
لماذا لم تزرها؟
I'll go visit her now.
سأذهب لزيارتها الآن.
Greetings, Mother.
تحياتي أمي.
It's too oily.
إنه زيتي للغاية.
Do you want to make me sicker?
هل تريد أن تجعلني أكثر مرضا؟
Who made the soup?
من صنع الحساء؟
Madam,
سيدتي،
I made it.
لقد فعلتها.
Did you?
هل فعلت؟
The soup you kindly made for me
الحساء الذي صنعته لي بلطف
should not be wasted.
لا ينبغي أن تضيع.
You drink it.
أنت تشربه.
Mother,
الأم،
I've been bustling around for a while
لقد كنت صاخبًا منذ فترة
and haven't eaten anything yet.
ولم تأكل أي شيء حتى الآن.
How about
ماذا عن
giving the soup to me?
يعطيني الحساء؟
Mom.
أم.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
I'm showing
أنا أعرض
you kindness
لك اللطف
but you made it look like
لكنك جعلته يبدو
I'm bullying you.
أنا أتنمر عليك.
You're all here.
أنتم جميعا هنا.
Chuxian, you're here too.
تشوشيان ، أنت هنا أيضًا.
You visited Mother
قمت بزيارة الأم
more frequently than I did.
أكثر مما فعلت.
Anyway,
على أي حال،
you are the most filial one
أنت الأكثر أبناء
among our brothers.
بين اخوتنا.
Good.
جيد.
Mother.
الأم.
How have you been?
كيف كان حالك؟
Still breathing.
مازال يتنفس.
How could you say that?
كيف تقول ذلك؟
You know what?
أتعلم؟
You can't imagine
لا يمكنك أن تتخيل
how much I've missed you these days.
كم اشتقت لك هذه الايام.
I...
أنا...
I was impulsive last time.
كنت متهورًا آخر مرة.
I'm here
أنا هنا
to apologize to you.
للاعتذار لك.
Lady Mo,
سيدة مو ،
why don't you and Chuxian take your leave?
لماذا لا تأخذ إجازتك أنت و (تشوكسيان)؟
Yes.
نعم.
Did I allow you to leave?
هل سمحت لك بالمغادرة؟
Jiang Chaoxi.
جيانغ تشوكسي.
Are you here to see me
هل انت هنا لتراني
or to plead for them?
أو الترافع لهم؟
Mother,
الأم،
don't get me wrong.
لا تفهموني خطأ.
Of course I'm here to see you.
بالطبع أنا هنا لرؤيتك.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Has Chuxian done something that made you angry?
هل فعل تشوشيان شيئًا أغضبك؟
Chuxian, how could you?
تشوشيان ، كيف يمكنك؟
You've been thoughtless
لقد كنت طائشًا
since you were young.
منذ أن كنت صغيرا.
Why did you make Mother angry so often?
لماذا تغضب أمي كثيرًا؟
Don't come here again.
لا تأتي إلى هنا مرة أخرى.
All you do is make Mother angry.
كل ما تفعله هو أن تغضب الأم.
Even looking at you is annoying.
حتى النظر إليك أمر مزعج.
Why are you still here?
لماذا لا تزال هنا؟
Leave now.
ارحل الآن.
Yes.
نعم.
You two…
أنت أيضا…
Don't be angry.
لا تغضب.
Calm down.
هدء من روعك.
If your condition gets worse,
إذا ساءت حالتك ،
I'll be worried sick.
سأكون مريضا قلقا.
I'm angry because of you.
أنا غاضب بسببك.
Leave now.
ارحل الآن.
No.
رقم.
You actually want me to stay, right?
أنت في الواقع تريدني أن أبقى ، أليس كذلك؟
You didn't mean what you said.
أنت لم تقصد ما قلته.
Mother,
الأم،
I'm here today
انا هنا اليوم
because of a tricky matter.
بسبب مسألة صعبة.
I want you to help me.
أريدك أن تساعدني.
What trouble have you got into this time?
ما المشكلة التي واجهتها في هذا الوقت؟
How could you
كيف استطعت
put it in such a hurtful way?
ضعها بطريقة مؤذية؟
It's a serious matter.
إنها مسألة جدية.
A serious matter.
أمر خطير.
I have been
لقد كنت
raising money
جمع المال
to build Futian Institution.
لبناء مؤسسة فوتيان.
I'm so bothered
أنا منزعج جدا
that my hair turned grizzled.
أن شعري أصبح أشيب.
I thought of
فكرت في
the valuable things you have.
الأشياء الثمينة التي لديك.
Mother…
الأم…
I knew you came to see me
علمت أنك أتيت لرؤيتي
with ulterior motives.
بدوافع خفية.
Get out!
اخرج!
I get a headache at the sight of you.
أصاب بصداع في مرأى منك.
Mother must not have had a headache
يجب ألا تعاني الأم من صداع
because of me.
بسببي.
Let me tell you.
دعني أخبرك.
It must be this vase
يجب أن تكون هذه المزهرية
that has affected my mother's mood.
التي أثرت على مزاج والدتي.
How dare you make my mother angry.
كيف تجرؤ على إثارة غضب والدتي.
It's fine.
لا بأس.
I'll move them away for you later.
سأبعدهم عنك لاحقًا.
Put it down.
ضعه أرضا، أنزله.
And this bottle.
وهذه الزجاجة.
You have to piss me off, right?
عليك أن تغضبني ، أليس كذلك؟
Alright.
على ما يرام.
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
But Her Ladyship
لكن سيدتها
has gone too far.
ذهب بعيدا جدا.
I don't mind being wronged.
أنا لا أمانع أن أظلم.
As long as you can live a stable
طالما يمكنك أن تعيش مستقرة
and safe life,
وحياة آمنة ،
I'm satisfied.
أنا راضٍ.
It's all my fault.
هذا كله خطأي.
I can't protect you.
لا استطيع حمايتك.
In front of outsiders,
أمام الغرباء ،
call me Lady Mo.
اتصل بي سيدة مو.
I was Her Ladyship's maid.
كنت خادمة سيادتها.
I accidentally
قمت بالخطأ
became Master's concubine.
أصبحت محظية الماجستير.
Of course Her Ladyship doesn't like me.
بالطبع سيدتها لا تحبني.
I'm used to it.
أنا معتاد على ذلك.
Just bear with it.
فقط تحمله.
As long as you're fine,
ما دمت بخير ،
I will be happy.
سأكون سعيدا.
Mother.
الأم.
I'll go beg Father
سأذهب وأتوسل أبي
to let us go.
لندعنا نذهب.
Don't do that!
لا تفعل ذلك!
Silly boy.
فتى سخيف.
How can you think like that?
كيف يمكنك التفكير بهذه الطريقة؟
All these years,
كل هذه السنوات،
Master and Her Ladyship
سيدها وسيادتها
have helped us a lot.
ساعدتنا كثيرا.
You should be polite
يجب أن تكون مهذبا
and focus on
والتركيز على
serving Young Master well.
يخدم السيد الشاب بشكل جيد.
You are his younger brother.
أنت أخوه الأصغر.
As long as you behave well
ما دمت تتصرف بشكل جيد
in front of him,
أمامه،
he will not
هو لن
treat you unfairly in the future.
يعاملك بشكل غير عادل في المستقبل.
Got it?
فهمتك؟
Don't mention
لا تذكر
about leaving again.
حول المغادرة مرة أخرى.
As long as we follow the rules,
طالما أننا نتبع القواعد ،
we will live a happy life.
سنعيش حياة سعيدة.
Got it, Mother.
حسنًا يا أمي.
Thank you for saving me today. Young Master.
شكرا لك لانقاذي اليوم.  المعلم الصغير.
We are brothers.
نحن اخوة.
Don't treat me as a stranger.
لا تعاملني كأنني غريب.
Call me Brother.
اتصل بي يا أخي.
Okay. Brother.
تمام.  أخ.
Have a seat.
تفضل بالجلوس.
Brother, what can I do for you?
أخي ، ماذا أفعل من أجلك؟
I need your help.
انا بحاجة الى مساعدتكم.
Help me complete the construction
ساعدني في استكمال البناء
of Futian Institution.
من مؤسسة فوتيان.
Futian Institution?
مؤسسة فوتيان؟
Brother, as you know,
أخي ، كما تعلم ،
I'm just a doctor.
أنا مجرد طبيب.
I can save people,
يمكنني إنقاذ الناس ،
but I'm afraid I can't do construction.
لكني أخشى أنني لا أستطيع البناء.
Who said you couldn't?
من قال أنك لا تستطيع؟
You study hard
أنت تدرس بجد
and love the people.
وأحب الناس.
You're a wise man.
أنت رجل حكيم.
It is such a good chance
إنها فرصة جيدة
to make contributions.
لتقديم مساهمات.
As long as you seize the chance
ما دمت تنتهز الفرصة
and work hard,
والعمل الجاد ،
Father and the officials
الأب والمسؤولون
will be impressed by you.
سوف يعجب بك.
But, Brother,
لكن يا أخي
as you know,
وانت عارف،
that's not what I want.
هذا ليس ما أريده.
I just want to live a peaceful life
أنا فقط أريد أن أعيش حياة سلمية
and protect Mother.
وحماية الأم.
That's all.
هذا كل شئ.
Third Brother.
الأخ الثالث.
I know
أنا أعرف
you want to protect Lady Mo,
تريد حماية ليدي مو ،
but you can't just
لكن لا يمكنك فقط
compromise.
مرونة.
You have to make yourself stronger.
عليك أن تجعل نفسك أقوى.
Only by being strong
فقط من خلال كونك قويًا
can you
هل تستطيع
be qualified and able to protect
أن يكون مؤهلاً وقادرًا على الحماية
who you want to protect.
من تريد حمايته.
I know
أنا أعرف
you want to change
انت تريد التغيير
and are eager to work for the people.
وهم حريصون على العمل من أجل الشعب.
Why don't you take this opportunity
لماذا لا تنتهز هذه الفرصة
as a good start?
كبداية جيدة؟
You know the will of the people
أنت تعرف إرادة الشعب
and strategies.
والاستراتيجيات.
This is the real you, right?
هذه هي حقيقتك ، أليس كذلك؟
You are ambitious
انت طموح
and devote yourself to the people.
وكرس نفسك للشعب.
I'm afraid
أنا خائف
that you acting dandyishly
أنك تتصرف بطريقة مخادعة
is just your disguise.
هو مجرد تمويه الخاص بك.
There's no need to say it clearly.
ليست هناك حاجة لقول ذلك بوضوح.
I have no choice.
ليس لدي خيار.
All the time,
طوال الوقت،
my uncle and his people
عمي وشعبه
have had strict control over me.
كان لي سيطرة صارمة.
In their hearts,
في قلوبهم
they want
هم يريدون
a foolish
أحمق
and obedient nephew.
وابن أخ مطيع.
But I couldn't find
لكن لم أجد
the evidence of his corruption.
دليل فساده.
I didn't expect
لم أتوقع
you and I were in the same boat.
كنت أنا وأنت في نفس القارب.
As you said,
كما قلت،
I couldn't even protect
لم أستطع حتى الحماية
the woman I love.
المرأة التي أحبها.
Third Brother.
الأخ الثالث.
You don't have to be like this.
ليس عليك أن تكون هكذا.
Don't worry
لا تقلق
about the wedding.
عن الزفاف.
I will never marry
لن اتزوج ابدا
Fengyi and Miss Nangong,
Fengyi و Miss Nangong ،
because Yunxi is the only one
لأن يونشى هو الوحيد
in my heart.
في قلبي.
Even if I have to marry someone,
حتى لو كان علي الزواج من شخص ما ،
I will only marry her.
سوف أتزوجها فقط.
I really admire
أنا معجب حقًا
your deep love.
حبك العميق.
Since you trust me,
بما أنك تثق بي ،
I will do my best.
سأبذل قصارى جهدي.
Okay.
تمام.
Except for the money
باستثناء المال
that Young Master pocketed from Her Ladyship,
التي انتزعها السيد الشاب من سيادتها ،
a total of 2,100 liangs
ما مجموعه 2100 ليانغ
are raised.
تربى.
To build Futian Institution,
لبناء مؤسسة فوتيان ،
the money is far from enough.
المال بعيد عن أن يكون كافيا.
It's all my uncle's fault.
كل هذا خطأ عمي.
All the officials
كل المسؤولين
are cowards.
جبناء.
No one dares to surpass him in donation.
لا أحد يجرؤ على تجاوزه في التبرع.
The current problem
المشكلة الحالية
is how to raise the money.
هي كيفية جمع المال.
Shut up!
اسكت!
After all,
بعد كل شيء،
I'm one of the intellectuals.
أنا من المثقفين.
I should have the right to speak.
يجب أن يكون لي الحق في الكلام.
Dr. Xian.
دكتور زيان.
Brother, I think
أخي ، على ما أعتقد
we can let Wuyan say something.
يمكننا أن ندع وويان يقول شيئًا ما.
Go ahead.
إنطلق.
I think we can
أعتقد أننا يمكن
be bold.
تكون جريئة.
Let's visit Xiao's Mansion at night
دعنا نزور قصر شياو في الليل
and steal the wealth
ويسرق الثروة
that Commander Xiao has coveted
الذي رغب فيه القائد شياو
in recent years.
فى السنوات الاخيرة.
The money can't be exposed.
لا يمكن كشف النقود.
He won't report it if he loses it.
لن يبلغ عنها إذا فقدها.
I think this is a good idea.
انا اعتقد انها فكرة جيدة.
You've become smarter. Wuyan.
لقد أصبحت أكثر ذكاءً.  وويان.
But
ولكن
it's a bit risky.
إنه محفوف بالمخاطر بعض الشيء.
Since this idea
منذ هذه الفكرة
is proposed by Wuyan,
مقترح من قبل Wuyan ،
let him have a try.
دعه يجرب.
If you succeed,
إذا نجحت ،
you'll be the hero of Futian Institution
ستكون بطل مؤسسة فوتيان
and be famous in the future.
وكن مشهورًا في المستقبل.
If you fail and get caught on the spot,
إذا فشلت ووقعت في الحال ،
you will be chopped
سوف يتم تقطيعك
by my uncle's soldiers.
من قبل جنود عمي.
I will remember
سوف اتذكر
to tell your story
لتروي قصتك
over and over again
مرارا وتكرارا
in the future.
فى المستقبل.
How about that?
ماذا عن ذلك؟
Wish you success.
أتمنى لك النجاح.
You must be joking.
لابد أنك تمزح.
I think this idea
أعتقد أن هذه الفكرة
is a little immature.
قليلا غير ناضج.
You talk first.
أنت تتحدث أولاً.
I'll think about it again.
سأفكر في الأمر مرة أخرى.
In order to raise donations,
من أجل جمع التبرعات ،
it seems that
يبدو أن
we need to start it from common people.
نحتاج أن نبدأها من عامة الناس.
Don't these officials
لا هؤلاء المسؤولين
care about their dignity the most?
تهتم بكرامتهم أكثر؟
Why don't they care about it
لماذا لا يهتمون بذلك
when it comes to donation?
عندما يتعلق الأمر بالتبرع؟
I have an idea.
لدي فكرة.
[Xiao's Mansion]
[قصر شياو]
Uncle,
اخو الام،
I'm here to tell you the good news.
أنا هنا لأخبرك بالأخبار السارة.
What's the good news?
ما هي الاخبار الجيدة؟
I did a great thing.
لقد فعلت شيئًا رائعًا.
If you know it,
اذا كنت تعرف ذلك،
you will be very happy.
سوف تكون سعيد جدا.
Yunxi,
يونشى ،
send the gift I bought
أرسل الهدية التي اشتريتها
to Fengyi first.
إلى Fengyi أولاً.
Yes.
نعم.
Where are you going?
إلى أين تذهب؟
No, this...
لا ، هذا ...
Come here.
تعال الى هنا.
Show Uncle.
تظهر العم.
Let him see.
دعه يرى.
What?
ماذا؟
It's a surprise.
انها مفاجئة.
Okay.
تمام.
Uncle, look.
العم ، انظر.
[The Honour Roll of Futian Institution Construction Donation]
[The Honor Roll of Futian Institution Donation Donation]
This is the list of donations for Futian Institution.
هذه قائمة التبرعات لمؤسسة فوتيان.
You top the list.
أنت على رأس القائمة.
I've sent someone
لقد أرسلت شخصًا ما
to post it on the notice board.
لنشره على لوحة الإعلانات.
I must
يجب علي
publicize this good deed you did, Uncle.
انشر هذا العمل الصالح ، عمي.
I'll let everyone in Cangyue City know
سأخبر الجميع في مدينة كانغيو
how powerful Uncle is.
ما مدى قوة العم.
No, this...
لا ، هذا ...
How can you put this on?
كيف يمكنك ارتداء هذا؟
Take it down.
انزله للأسفل.
It is such a good deed.
هذا عمل جيد.
How can I take it down?
كيف يمكنني إنزاله؟
I must publicize this thing.
يجب أن أنشر هذا الشيء.
Everyone in Cangyue City
الجميع في مدينة كانغيو
must know it.
يجب أن تعرف ذلك.
I...
أنا...
Stop shaking my chair.
توقف عن هز الكرسي.
I mean
أعني
you are too high-profile.
أنت شخصية رفيعة جدًا.
This is against
هذا ضد
my low-key style,
أسلوبي البسيط ،
right?
الصحيح؟
Uncle,
اخو الام،
you're wrong.
أنت مخطئ.
Didn't you say
لم تقل
in the meeting hall
في قاعة الاجتماع
that you did a lot of good deeds
أنك فعلت الكثير من الأعمال الصالحة
and donated a lot of money?
وتبرعت بالكثير من المال؟
But we've never heard of
لكننا لم نسمع به من قبل
these good things.
هذه الأشياء الجيدة.
So,
لذا،
you can be a low-key person,
يمكنك أن تكون شخصًا متواضعًا ،
but you should do things in a high profile.
ولكن يجب عليك القيام بأشياء في مكانة مرموقة.
If you do it well,
إذا كنت تفعل ذلك بشكل جيد ،
Uncle, your modesty
عمك تواضعك
will reach a new level.
سوف تصل إلى مستوى جديد.
So,
لذا،
in order to make Uncle
من أجل جعل العم
become such a person,
كن مثل هذا الشخص ،
this time, I must keep a high profile.
هذه المرة ، يجب أن أحافظ على مكانة عالية.
I want everyone in Cangyue City
أريد الجميع في مدينة كانغيو
to know
لتعرف
how Uncle
كيف العم
does things.
يفعل الأشياء.
You...
أنت...
Uncle,
اخو الام،
we must leave a name for doing good deeds.
يجب أن نترك اسمًا لفعل الخير.
We should not only leave your name,
يجب ألا نترك اسمك فقط ،
but also make it bold and bigger.
ولكن أيضًا اجعلها جريئة وأكبر.
-You… -You know what?
-أنت… -تعرف ماذا؟
I'll make your...
سأجعل ...
Cousin.
ابن عم.
Cousin, you're here.
ابن عم ، أنت هنا.
Miss.
يغيب.
Have you seen Miss Yunxi?
هل رأيت الآنسة يونكسي؟
Is Yunxi here?
هل يونشى هنا؟
Where is she?
أين هي؟
I bought you
اشتريت لك
some gifts.
بعض الهدايا.
I asked Yunxi to send them to you.
طلبت من Yunxi أن يرسلها إليك.
Maybe the Xiao's Mansion is too big,
ربما قصر شياو كبير جدًا ،
so she got lost.
لذلك ضاعت.
But she's old enough now.
لكنها كبيرة بما يكفي الآن.
Just leave her alone.
فقط اتركها وشأنها.
Okay.
تمام.
We'd better go find her.
من الأفضل أن نذهب ونبحث عنها.
If Miss Yunxi gets lost,
إذا ضاعت الآنسة Yunxi ،
she'll be worried.
ستكون قلقة.
Go and find her.
اذهب وابحث عنها.
Cousin.
ابن عم.
I heard that you had been busy
سمعت أنك كنت مشغولا
raising donations
جمع التبرعات
for Futian Institution these days.
لمؤسسة فوتيان هذه الأيام.
Have you raised enough money?
هل جمعت ما يكفي من المال؟
Cousin.
ابن عم.
Of course not.
بالطبع لا.
We still need a lot of money.
ما زلنا بحاجة إلى الكثير من المال.
Father.
أب.
You have to donate more.
عليك التبرع بالمزيد
Uncle donated 100 liangs.
تبرع العم بـ 100 ليانغ.
Only 100 liangs?
100 ليانغ فقط؟
You are so stingy.
أنت بخيل جدا.
How can I
كيف يمكنني
establish myself in the Noble Lady's circle?
أضع نفسي في دائرة السيدة النبيلة؟
Nangong Siyan
نانغونغ سيان
will laugh at me.
سوف تضحك علي.
I'm stingy.
أنا بخيل.
What do you know?
ماذا تعرف؟
100 liangs.
100 ليانغ.
100 liangs are enough.
100 ليانغ كافية.
My monthly salary
راتبي الشهري
is only 100 liangs.
فقط 100 ليانغ.
You don't need to take care of the family,
لست بحاجة لرعاية الأسرة ،
so you don't know that the daily necessities are expensive.
حتى لا تعرف أن الضروريات اليومية باهظة الثمن.
Take a look.
إلق نظرة.
There are so many people
هناك الكثير من الناس
living on
يعيش على
my salary
راتبي
this month.
هذا الشهر.
There's really no money
لا يوجد مال حقًا
in the Xiao's Mansion.
في قصر شياو.
Nonsense!
كلام فارغ!
You spend hundreds of liangs
كنت تنفق مئات من liangs
buying cumumber for your face every month.
شراء الكمبر لوجهك كل شهر.
And facial masks
وأقنعة الوجه
which can
والتي يمكن
whiten your skin.
تبيض بشرتك.
Enough.
كافية.
Stop talking nonsense.
توقف عن الكلام هراء.
Feed your rabbit.
أطعم أرنبك.
No.
رقم.
This concerns my dignity.
هذا يتعلق بكرامتي.
I can't let Father
لا أستطيع السماح لأبي
mess around like this.
العبث بهذا الشكل.
How dare you?
كيف تجرؤ؟
You...
أنت...
Fine.
بخير.
I have an idea
لدي فكرة
which can both save her face
التي يمكن أن تنقذ وجهها
and save your embarrassment.
وحفظ إحراجك.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
How about
ماذا عن
donating some money first
التبرع ببعض المال أولا
and setting an example for the officials?
وضرب قدوة للمسؤولين؟
With you as the leader,
معك كقائد
the officials and rich merchants
المسؤولين والتجار الأغنياء
will be encouraged
سيتم تشجيعه
to donate.
للتبرع.
When I get
عندما أحصل
the donations,
التبرعات ،
I'll return your money to you.
سأعيد أموالك إليك.
Cousin...
ابن عم...
I'll double it for you,
سأضاعفها لك ،
okay?
حسنا؟
Write an IOU.
اكتب IOU.
A 5,000-liang note. Take it.
ورقة نقدية فئة 5000 ليانغ.  خذها.
Five thousand?
خمسة آلاف؟
Thank you, Uncle.
أشكرك عمي.
You two!
أنت أيضا!
One is my future husband,
واحد هو زوجي المستقبلي ،
and the other is my father.
والآخر هو والدي.
How despicable you are!
كم أنت حقير!
You even faked the good deeds.
حتى أنك زورت الحسنات.
You guys, search separately.
يا رفاق ، ابحثوا بشكل منفصل.
Brother,
أخ،
where is Miss Fengyi's yard?
أين ساحة الآنسة فنجي؟
Listen.
استمع.
My uncle is like
عمي مثل
a loach in the water.
لوش في الماء.
He is too cunning.
إنه ماكر للغاية.
His cunning mind
عقله الماكر
is devoted to striving for power and profit all his life.
يكرس نفسه للسعي من أجل القوة والربح طوال حياته.
If he owns Fengchi,
إذا كان يمتلك Fengchi ،
I'm afraid Cangyue City is over.
أخشى أن مدينة كانجيو قد انتهت.
It was such a good opportunity.
كانت هذه فرصة جيدة.
I missed it.
فاتني ذلك.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I'll find a chance to bring you here again.
سأجد فرصة لإحضارك إلى هنا مرة أخرى.
According to my observation today,
حسب ملاحظتي اليوم ،
the Xiao's Mansion is heavily guarded
قصر شياو يخضع لحراسة مشددة
and Commander Xiao is suspicious.
والقائد شياو مشبوه.
I'm afraid it will be very hard
أخشى أن يكون الأمر صعبًا جدًا
to find another chance
للعثور على فرصة أخرى
to enter his study.
لدخول دراسته.
Yes.
نعم.
He is too cunning.
إنه ماكر للغاية.
It's not easy
انها ليست سهلة
to get something from him.
للحصول على شيء منه.
Fortunately, we found something.
لحسن الحظ ، وجدنا شيئًا.
We'll find another chance.
سنجد فرصة أخرى.
Did your fish take the bait?
هل أخذت سمكتك الطُعم؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
I'm going to spread this.
سأقوم بنشر هذا.
With my uncle as the leader,
مع عمي كقائد ،
I believe
أعتقد
all the officials will follow him.
كل المسؤولين سيتبعونه.
The money problem will be solved.
سيتم حل مشكلة المال.
Then how to deal with
ثم كيف نتعامل معها
the refund?
برد؟
It's hard, but we still need to do it.
إنه صعب ، لكننا ما زلنا بحاجة إلى القيام به.
There is a way out.
هناك طريقة للخروج.
Trust me.
صدقني.
There is no obstacle that can't be overcome.
لا توجد عقبة لا يمكن التغلب عليها.